[upbeat music]
[all] One, two, three, go!
一、二、三，开始！
Keep your stick straight!
保持你的棍子直！
Stop throwing at my face.
别再往我脸上扔了。
- Foul! You guys wiggle-woggled. - No, I didn't.
- 犯规！你们扭来扭去的。 - 不，我没有。
- Yes, you did. - No, I didn't.
- 是的，你有。 - 不，我没有。
- Do you believe this, Anne? - I know. That was clearly an illegal wiggle-woggle.
- 安妮，你相信这个吗？ - 我知道。那明显是非法的扭动。
- No, I didn't! - Yes, you did!
- 不，我没有！ - 是的，你有！
No, I didn't!
不，我没有！
- What are you kids doing?
- 你们这些孩子在做什么？
[plungers pop]
[马桶塞弹出]
We're trying to play Toilet Stick Round Thingy Toss.
我们正在尝试玩马桶塞圆环投掷游戏。
Yeah, well, when your mother and I
是啊，不过，当我和你妈妈
invented Toilet Stick Round Thingy Toss,
发明马桶塞圆环投掷游戏时，
we intended for it to be taken seriously.
我们希望它能被认真对待。
I'm trying, Dad, but Wiggle and Woggle over here are making a mockery of the sport.
我正在努力，爸爸，但Wiggle和Woggle在这里把这项运动当儿戏。
You know, maybe it's time we got these kids
你知道吗，也许是我们该给这些孩子
some after-school activities.
安排一些课外活动的时候了。
Good parenting, Mom.
好样的，妈妈。
However, since chess club ended and my Japanese language club
然而，自从国际象棋俱乐部结束，我的日语俱乐部
doesn't start for another san shukan--
还有三周才开始——
that's three weeks in Japanese--
日语里是三周——
I've decided to take a well-deserved break.
我决定好好休息一下，这是应得的。
And we're taking it with him.
我们要和他一起放松。
Well, you've got a week to find something constructive
你有一个星期的时间去找些有益的事情
to do with your free time,
来打发你的空闲时间，
or your mother and I are gonna find something for you.
否则你妈妈和我会替你找事情做。
Hey, you could always come with me to my slow-cooker class.
嘿，你可以跟我一起去上慢炖锅课程。
This week, we are making an Italian feast in one pot!
这周我们要在一个锅里做出意大利大餐！
We're gonna pass on that in one word--
我们会用一个词拒绝——
no.
不。
[horn plays]
[号角声]
I told you Tuba Monster was real.
我告诉过你大号怪兽是真的。
I have great news.
我有个好消息。
Ms. Bing asked me to play tuba
宾女士让我在学校巡回乐团中演奏大号。
in the school's traveling orchestra.
我们每个星期六都可以在不同的学校表演。
We get to perform at a different school every Saturday.
我能为我大号来个“哟呵”吗？
Can I get a boo-ya for my tuba?
巡回乐团，哇。
Traveling orchestra, wow.
当我们说你们孩子应该参与
When we said you kids should get involved
课外活动时，我们并不是指所有的活动。
in after-school activities, we didn't mean all of them.
在课后活动中，我们并不是指所有的活动。
Yeah, sweetie, don't you think
是的，亲爱的，你不觉得
maybe you're spreading yourself a little thin?
也许你把自己分散得太开了吗？
But I love playing the tuba,
但我喜欢吹大号，
and I'm getting pretty good at it.
而且我在这方面已经相当不错了。
Plus, it makes the boys do this.
另外，这会让男孩们这样做。
[loud horn note]
[响亮的号声]
[laughs]
[笑]
Dawn, you've got soccer
道恩，你有足球训练
and your chores and your homework and--
还有你的家务、作业和--
Look, I know it sounds like a lot,
听着，我知道这听起来很多，
but at least give me a chance to try.
但至少给我一个机会去尝试。
I promise I can totally do it all.
我保证我完全可以做到所有。
That's why everyone calls me Do-it-all Dawn.
这就是为什么大家都叫我全能Dawn。
We don't call you that.
我们没这么叫你。
I thought we called her, "Know-It-All Dawn."
我以为我们叫她，“万事通Dawn。”
Not to her face.
不是当面叫的。
Okay, but if your grades suffer at all,
好吧，但如果你的成绩有任何下降，
you're gonna have to drop something.
你就得放弃一些事情。
- Oh, thank you. - Hold on.
- 哦，谢谢你。 - 等等。
It's bad enough you drag us to Dawn's stupid soccer games.
你带我们去看Dawn那无聊的足球赛已经够糟糕了。
Now we have to be dragged to her even stupider tuba concerts?
现在我们还得被拉去听她更无聊的圆号音乐会？
- Come on. - I mean, it's not fair.
- 拜托。 - 我是说，这不公平。
H-h-h-hold on a sec.
等一下。
We are Harpers, and we support each other's stupid activities.
我们是Harpers家的人，我们支持彼此的愚蠢活动。
- Tom! - What?
- Tom！ - 怎么了？
Oh, it's just the way the kids talk.
哦，这只是孩子们的说话方式。
It means fresh and cool.
意思是新鲜和酷。
Like, "Hey.
比如，“嘿。
Stupid pants, Anne."
安，这裤子真蠢。”
Trust me, I know this.
相信我，我知道这个。
That's why they call me Knows-the-way-the-kids-talk Tom.
这就是为什么他们叫我懂孩子们说话方式的汤姆。
I thought we called him The Bald Eagle.
我以为我们叫他秃鹰。
Not to his face.
不是当面叫的。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na, hey! ♪
♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
[whistling melody]
[口哨旋律]
♪ ♪
[rhythmic clapping] ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
[有节奏的拍手] ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
♪ ♪
♪ Na na na na na-na ♪
♪ Na na na na na-na, hey! ♪
- ♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na na na na na-na ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
[upbeat music]
[playing tuba]
♪ ♪
Hey, how's it going?
嘿，怎么样？
Aww, that's so sweet.
哦，真贴心。
You guys came backstage to check on me before I went on.
你们在我上台前特意来后台看我。
Yeah, totally.
是啊，当然。
On a completely unrelated note, is there any food back here?
说个完全不相关的事，这里有什么吃的吗？
Gee, thanks for the support, guys.
哎，谢谢你们的支持，伙计们。
You're welcome.
不客气。
But seriously, where's the food?
但说真的，吃的在哪儿？
There's no food.
这里没有吃的。
Ricky's getting cranky!
瑞奇要发脾气了！
At least when we get dragged to your soccer games,
至少我们被拉去看你踢足球时，
there's a snack shack.
还有个小卖部。
Plus, all those free orange slices and juice boxes.
另外，还有那些免费的橘子片和果汁盒。
Um, those are for the players.
嗯，那些是给球员们的。
I'm a playa.
我是个玩家。
[loud tuba note] [all] Ah!
[响亮的低音号声] [众人] 啊！
- I hate that thing. - Stupid tuba.
- 我讨厌那玩意儿。- 笨拙的低音号。
I'm still hungry.
我还是饿。
So what kind of music you think they're gonna play?
所以你觉得他们会演奏什么样的音乐？
Not classical, right?
不是古典音乐，对吧？
Probably some cool jazz or some uptown funk?
可能是些酷炫的爵士乐或者上城放克？
Tom, it's the Edgewood Classical Orchestra.
汤姆，这是埃奇伍德古典管弦乐团。
Pretty sure they're gonna be playing classical music.
我敢肯定他们会演奏古典音乐。
- Oh.
哦。
I know it's not your favorite,
我知道这不是你最喜欢的，
but can't you just hold it together for an hour for Dawn?
但你就不能为了Dawn忍耐一个小时吗？
I can't hold it all, Anne. That's the problem.
我忍不了，Anne。问题就在这儿。
What?
什么？
When I was a toddler,
当我还是个幼儿时，
I was resistant to potty training, and...
我对如厕训练有抵触，而且...
I was resistant to potty training,
我对如厕训练有抵触，
so my mother used classical music to relax me, but it worked too well.
所以我妈妈用古典音乐来让我放松，但效果太好了。
Now every time I hear Bach, Little Tommy has to tinkle.
现在每次我听到巴赫，小汤米就得去小便。
But you're Big Tommy now.
但你现在是汤米大了。
You drove us here.
是你开车带我们来的。
You're right. I can control this.
你说得对。我能控制这个。
- Yeah. - I'm a grown man. - Yeah. - [chuckles]
是的。 - 我是个成年人了。 - 是的。 - [轻笑]
Ladies and gentlemen, The Best of Bach.
女士们先生们，《巴赫精选》。
[classical music]
[古典音乐]
[gasps]
[吸气声]
Little Tommy has to tinkle!
小汤米得去小便！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
You need a hand there, Dawn?
需要帮忙吗，Dawn？
No, I'm good, just trying to squeeze
不用，我很好，只是想在必须做作业之前挤出一点时间练习--
a little practice in before I have to do my homewor--
哦，亲爱的！你还好吗？
Oh, honey! Are you okay?
[咳嗽] 看情况。
[coughs] Depends.
那是我的腿吗？
Is that my leg?
不，那是模特的。
No, that's the mannequin's.
[Dawn叹气]
[Dawn sighs]
亲爱的，你确定没有承担太多吗？
Hon, are you sure you're not taking on too much?
- 不，我很好。 - 好的。
- No. I'm good. - Okay.
- 我是无所不能的Dawn-- - 哦，哦！
- I am Do-it-all Daw-- - Oh, oh!
- 我是无所不能的道尔-- - 哦，哦！
- Look, I know what you're thinking,
- 看，我知道你在想什么，
but I also just started taking
但我刚刚开始上
a class called, "How to Fall Completely on Purpose."
一门叫做“如何故意完全摔倒”的课。
Nailed it.
完美掌握。
[plays tuba]
[吹奏大号]
Well, well, well,
哎呀，哎呀，哎呀，
if it isn't the Saturday-Stealer.
这不是那个偷走周六的人吗。
The Weekend-Waster.
浪费周末的人。
The girl who plays tuba so we can't do what we want
那个吹大号的女孩，让我们不能做我们想做的事
because we're stuck at her stupid recitals...er.
因为我们被困在她的愚蠢演奏会上...
Guys, I feel really bad
伙计们，我真的感到很抱歉
that my recitals are ruining your weekends.
我的演奏会毁了你们的周末。
So you're gonna quit?
所以你要放弃吗？
Yes, I'm gonna quit.
是的，我要放弃。
Feeling bad.
感到内疚。
Maybe you guys should listen to Dad
也许你们应该听爸爸的
and get your own activities so you can ruin your own weekends,
去参加自己的活动，这样你们就可以毁了自己的周末，
'cause I love mine and I'm not giving them up.
因为我喜欢我的周末，我不会放弃它们。
[loud tuba note] [all] Ah!
【大声的圆号音】【所有人】啊！
[sighs]
[叹气]
I can't believe we have to suffer through another one
真不敢相信我们还得再忍受一次
of Dawn's snackless concerts.
没有零食的Dawn的音乐会。
[bell rings] - Hey, kids.
[铃声响起] - 嘿，孩子们。
Look what The Bald Eagle dug out of the storage room
看看秃鹰从储藏室里挖出来的
for the baseball display.
棒球展品。
Caw-caw! Caw-caw!
哇-哇！哇-哇！
Hey, Bald Eagle just gave me an idea.
嘿，秃鹰给了我一个主意。
What if we didn't have to suffer through another concert?
如果我们不必再忍受另一场音乐会呢？
What if we could convince him
如果我们能说服他
to let us borrow the hot dog cart this weekend?
让我们这个周末借用热狗车怎么样？
That's brilliant.
这主意太棒了。
Not only will we have food,
我们不仅会有食物，
but we can sell hot dogs to all those other starving people.
还可以把热狗卖给所有那些饥饿的人。
And Dad'll be happy because it's an extracurricular activity.
而且爸爸会高兴，因为这是课外活动。
Dicky, you're a genius.
迪基，你真是个天才。
Genius?
天才？
I just thought it would be fun to ride around the parking lot.
我只是觉得在停车场里骑来骑去会很有趣。
But yeah, genius feels right.
不过，是的，天才这个词很合适。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
The capital of Utah is Salt Lake City.
犹他州的首府是盐湖城。
The capital of Virginia is Richmond.
弗吉尼亚州的首府是里士满。
The capital of Rhode Island is--
罗德岛州的首府是——
[whistle blows]
[哨声响起]
Harper! What are you doing?
哈珀！你在干什么？
Sorry, Coach.
对不起，教练。
I was up late practicing the tuba.
我昨晚练习大号到很晚。
I have a big test tomorrow, and I really need to study.
我明天有个大考试，我真的需要学习。
Oh, well, why didn't you say so?
哦，那你为什么不早说呢？
How about we take a break from practice,
我们何不暂停练习，
get some flash cards, and the whole team can quiz you?
拿些抽认卡，整个团队可以帮你测验？
- Really? - No!
- 真的吗？ - 不！
[blows whistle] Study on your own time.
[吹哨] 自己找时间学习。
Sorry, Coach! Won't happen again!
对不起，教练！不会再发生了！
I'm 100% focused on soccer starting right now!
我现在100%专注于足球！
Okay.
好的。
Soccer. Soccer.
足球。足球。
Socc-ramento is the capital of California.
萨克拉门托是加利福尼亚的首府。
The capital of New York is--ball!
纽约的首府是——球！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
Dawn, we are on in two minutes.
黎明，我们两分钟后开始。
- Time to put the notebook away. - Okay. Just one sec. I didn't get a chance to finish my homework yesterday--
- 该把笔记本收起来了。 - 好的。稍等一下。我昨天没机会完成作业——
Just put it away.
先收起来吧。
Okay. Almost done. Almost--
好的。快好了。快——
Oh!
哦！
[horn plays]
[号角声]
Well--
嗯——
[bell ringing] - Dogs! Get your hot dogs!
[铃声] - 狗狗们！来买热狗！
Doggy, doggy, doggy.
狗狗，狗狗，狗狗。
Who wants a hot doggy?
谁想要一个热狗？
Can I get a regular dog, and could you warm the bun, please?
我可以要一个普通的热狗吗？还有，你能把面包加热一下吗？
No problem.
没问题。
Lonely pooch in a warm slipper!
穿着温暖拖鞋的孤独小狗！
Flying in hot.
热腾腾地送来。
You know, I got to hand it to the boys. They're really working hard back there.
你知道吗，我得承认那些小伙子们。他们真的在后面很努力工作。
[raspy] Yeah, I'm glad I let 'em use the cart.
是啊，我很高兴让他们使用这辆推车。
Tom, this is silly.
汤姆，这太傻了。
Just drink some water.
就喝点水吧。
No, I haven't had any liquids in 24 hours.
不，我已经24小时没有摄入任何液体了。
[sighs]
[叹气]
They can play all the Bach they want.
他们可以尽情演奏巴赫的所有作品。
My river has run dry.
我的河流已经干涸。
The Edgewood Classical Orchestra
埃奇伍德古典乐团
is proud to perform Toccata in D Minor by Bach.
自豪地演奏巴赫的《D小调托卡塔》。
But first, something by Mozart.
但首先，来点莫扎特的作品。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Bach, Bach lemonade, around the corner,
巴赫，巴赫柠檬水，转角处，
Mozart's made.
莫扎特的作品。
[gasps]
（喘气声）
[yelps]
[upbeat music]
[all] Ooh.
And I thought investing my hot dog money in savings bonds
我还以为把我的热狗钱投资在储蓄债券上
was brilliant.
是绝顶聪明呢。
But this...
但这个...
I mean, Nicky, bravo.
我是说，Nicky，太棒了。
To Nicky, Ricky, Dicky, & Dogs!
为Nicky，Ricky，Dicky和狗狗们干杯！
[all grunt]
Whoops. I'll get that.
哎呀。我来处理。
No need, my good man.
不用了，我的好先生。
Allow my hot dog money to take care of it.
让我用热狗的钱来解决它。
Lucas.
卢卡斯。
I bought the freedom to never do chores again.
我买了永远不用再做家务的自由。
Ah, Mr. D,
啊，D先生，
always with the messes.
总是有这些麻烦。
Let me get that for you.
让我来帮你处理。
He doesn't just get my messes,
他不仅仅处理我的麻烦，
he gets me.
他还理解我。
I think we need to take a minute
我想我们需要花点时间
to appreciate how lucky we are.
要感激我们的幸运。
Agreed.
同意。
If it wasn't for Dawn and her kooky tuba dreams,
如果不是因为Dawn和她那古怪的大号梦想，
we wouldn't have any of this.
我们不会有这一切。
To Dawn!
为Dawn干杯！
I got you, Mr. D.
我懂你，D先生。
[vacuum hums]
[吸尘器嗡嗡声]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
The capital of New Mexico is Santa Fe.
新墨西哥州的首府是圣菲。
The capital of Colorado is...
科罗拉多州的首府是...
[sighs] Sleepytown.
[叹气] 沉睡镇。
What's wrong with Dawn?
Dawn怎么了？
Yeah. Everybody knows the capital of Colorado is a C.
是啊。大家都知道科罗拉多的首府是C。
[dog barks] - I'm Do-it-all Dawn!
[狗叫] - 我是多面手Dawn！
What am I doing?
我在做什么？
Maybe Mom and Dad were right.
也许爸爸妈妈是对的。
Maybe I can't do it all.
也许我不能什么都做。
I love the tuba, but maybe I have to give it up.
我喜欢大号，但也许我得放弃它。
If Dawn quits band, our hot dog business is over.
如果Dawn退出乐队，我们的热狗生意就完了。
No more hot dogs.
没有热狗了。
No more cotton candy.
不再有棉花糖。
No more Lucas.
不再有卢卡斯。
Oh, that reminds me.
哦，这让我想起来了。
More, Lucas.
更多的，卢卡斯。
Got to get it in while he's still here.
得在他还在这里的时候抓紧时间。
[upbeat music]
What am I gonna do?
我该怎么办？
Am I Do-it-all Dawn?
我是无所不能的Dawn吗？
Am I not Do-it-all Dawn?
我不是无所不能的Dawn吗？
Okay, all clear, Tom.
好了，都清楚了，Tom。
She's not playing Mozart.
她没有在演奏莫扎特。
Mom, Dad...
妈妈，爸爸...
Relax. She's Do-it-all Dawn.
放松。她是无所不能的Dawn。
There's no way she's really gonna quit.
她不可能真的要放弃。
- [sighs] You were right.
你是对的。
I've got a lot on my plate, and...
我有很多事情要做，而且...
She's gonna quit!
她要放弃了！
It's impossible for me to--
我根本不可能...
Study on an empty stomach.
空腹学习。
The only thing this girl doesn't have on her plate is food.
这个女孩唯一没有的就是食物。
Look how light she is.
看看她多轻。
What's happening?
发生什么事了？
See? She's delirious.
看吧？她都神志不清了。
She doesn't even know what's happening.
她甚至不知道发生了什么。
What are you doing? Put me down.
你在干什么？放我下来。
[grunts]
（咕哝声）
Okay, I asked for that.
好吧，我自找的。
You can't quit band.
你不能退出乐队。
Why do you care if I quit?
你为什么在乎我是否退出？
What kind of message does that send to all the girls
这对所有把你视为大号演奏榜样的女孩们传递了什么信息？
who look up to you as a tuba-playing role model?
那些把你视为大号演奏榜样的女孩们会怎么想？
Yeah, you're Do-it-all Dawn.
是啊，你是无所不能的Dawn。
What do you say?
你怎么说？
Will you stick with band
你会坚持留在乐队里，
and be an inspiration to girls everywhere?
成为各地女孩们的灵感来源吗？
I don't get it.
我不明白。
I thought you guys were happy to have your Saturdays back.
我以为你们会很高兴周末能空出来。
Oh, I get it now.
哦，我现在明白了。
You don't want me to quit
你不想我退出，
'cause you'll have to give up your stupid hot dog business.
因为你得放弃你那愚蠢的热狗生意。
Pfft. What?
噗，什么？
That's crazy talk.
你在胡说八道呢。
"Get a hot dog fridge," I said.
我说过‘买个热狗冰箱’。
"No, I want a butler," you said.
你说‘不，我想要个管家’。
Why did we even have that meeting?
我们当初为什么要开那个会呢？
This isn't about our hot dog business.
这不是关于我们热狗生意的事。
Yeah, we'd give up that cart in a second
是的，如果我们觉得对你好，我们一秒都不会犹豫放弃那车热狗。
if it was the right thing for you.
如果那是对你最好的选择的话。
Look, I'm so tired right now,
现在我累得不行，
I don't know what to believe.
都不知道该相信什么了。
But it doesn't matter anyway.
但无论如何，这都不重要。
I physically can't do it all.
我实在无法做到所有事情。
Well, what if we helped you do it all?
如果我们帮你一起做呢？
I can help you with your homework.
我可以帮你做作业。
And I can carry your tuba.
我还可以帮你拿大号。
[phone ringing]
（电话铃声）
Oh, and I'll answer all your calls, so you can stay focused.
哦，我会接听你所有的电话，这样你就可以专心了。
Lucas!
卢卡斯！
Phone.
电话。
Dicky Harper's sister's phone.
迪基·哈珀的妹妹的电话。
This is Lucas.
这里是Lucas。
Wow, this could actually work,
哇，这实际上可能行得通，
unless they move my soccer game to the exact same time
除非他们把我的足球比赛改到和我下次乐队表演完全相同的时间。
as my next band performance.
是的，全能小姐，
Uh, Ms. Do-it-all,
他们刚刚把你的足球比赛改到了和你下次乐队表演完全相同的时间。
they just moved your soccer game to the exact same time
什么？不！那天我有一个大号独奏。
as your next band performance.
如果所有事情都在同一时间，我怎么可能都做到？
What? No! I have a big tuba solo that day.
（Nicky咕哝）
How am I supposed to do it all if it's all at the same time?
也许我应该帮你拿书。
[Nicky grunts]
我甚至看不清我往哪儿走，带着这东西。
Maybe I should carry your books instead.
也许我应该帮你拿书。
I can't even see where I'm going with this thing.
我甚至看不清自己要去哪儿。
That's it!
就是这样！
I can hide behind Dawn's tuba
我可以躲在Dawn的大号后面，
and pretend to play while she's at her soccer game.
在她去踢足球的时候假装演奏。
Then, we can cause a distraction at the game.
然后，我们可以在比赛中制造干扰。
She'll run over, play her solo,
她会跑过来，演奏她的独奏，
and run back to the game before anyone notices.
然后在任何人注意到之前跑回比赛。
Nicky, you're a genius.
Nicky，你真是个天才。
I thought I was a genius.
我还以为我是个天才呢。
You know, you're a little loosey-goosey with the G word.
你知道，你对'天才'这个词用得有点随便。
This week's concert
这周的音乐会
is just across the park from the soccer field.
就在公园对面的足球场。
Dawn, what do you think?
Dawn，你怎么看？
[snoring]
[打呼噜]
I got this, Mr. D.
我搞定这个，D先生。
He's the best butler hot dog money can buy.
他是最好的管家热狗，钱能买到的。
[upbeat music]
[轻快的音乐]
- Ugh. - Come on.
唉。
- Almost there. - [groans]
快到了。
Almost there.
Wait for the bell.
等铃响。
I'm not gonna make it, Anne!
我赶不上了，安妮！
Is this how old people dance?
这是老人跳舞的方式吗？
[bell rings]
（铃响）
[both] Ah!
（两人）啊！
[laughs]
（笑）
- I made it! - Yes!
我做到了！
- Made it! - [laughs]
做到了！
Do we want to know what's happening here?
我们想知道这里发生了什么吗？
Oh, I'm trying to recondition your father
哦，我正在试图重新训练你父亲
not to give into the urge to use the men's room
不要一听到巴赫的音乐
whenever he hears Bach.
就忍不住想去男洗手间。
So you're potty training your husband?
所以你在训练你丈夫上厕所？
Yes.
是的。
But aren't you afraid you're just transferring Dad's trigger
但你不怕只是把爸爸的触发点
from classical music to the sound of bells?
从古典音乐转移到了铃声吗？
Oh, sweetie, I don't think it works that way.
哦，亲爱的，我觉得不是那样工作的。
Whew.
唷。
[bell rings]
[铃声响起]
[gasps]
[倒抽一口气]
[yelps]
[惊叫]
What do you know? It does work that way.
你知道吗？确实如此。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
Cello. Violin.
大提琴。小提琴。
One tuba.
一个低音号。
Where's Dawn?
Dawn在哪里？
[high-pitched voice] Right here, Ms. Bing.
[高音调的声音] 在这里，Bing女士。
Dawn, what are you doing?
Dawn，你在做什么？
Take your position.
站到你的位置上去。
Yes, Ms. Bing.
是的，Bing女士。
- That's not your position. - Sorry.
那不是你的位置。抱歉。
You know how us girls are.
你知道我们女孩子嘛。
Always forgetting stuff.
总是忘东忘西的。
[giggles]
（咯咯笑）
[Lobo] Nice save, Harper.
（Lobo）救得好，Harper。
- Keep it up. - Will do, Coach.
继续保持。会的，教练。
At least until Dicky can find a way to delay the game.
至少在Dicky找到方法延迟比赛之前。
Come on, Dicky.
快点，Dicky。
[sprinklers turn on]
（喷水器开启）
[children screaming]
[孩子们尖叫]
- All right, everyone off the field
好了，大家离开场地
until we can turn off the sprinklers.
直到我们能把喷水器关掉。
- And I messed with the timer,
我调整了定时器，
so that won't happen for another 27 minutes.
所以还要再等27分钟。
I think we all know who the real genius is.
我想我们都知道谁是真正的天才。
Yes, we do.
是的，我们知道。
[classical music]
[古典音乐]
Dawn, it's time for your solo.
黎明，轮到你的独奏了。
Stand up.
站起来。
[thinking] Where is she?
她在哪儿？
[flat tuba note]
（低沉的土巴号音）
♪ ♪
There she is.
她在那儿。
Okay. Ricky needs a plan.
好的。Ricky需要一个计划。
[Dawn] Ow!
（Dawn）哎哟！
- Whoopsie.
哎呀。
Dropped some girly business behind this curtain.
把一些女孩的东西落在这帘子后面了。
[playing tuba]
（吹土巴号）
♪ ♪
[applause]
[掌声]
Nice job, Dawn.
干得好，Dawn。
I know, I rocked it, not to toot my own horn.
我知道，我表现得很好，不是在自吹自擂。
But, just to be clear,
但是，为了清楚起见，
that was totally me tooting my own horn the entire show.
整场演出都是我在自吹自擂。
Got to go.
我得走了。
Hey, there's our little tuba star.
嘿，那是我们的小号角明星。
Oh! [laughs]
哦！[笑]
You were so great, honey.
你表现得真棒，亲爱的。
I know, I rocked it, not to toot my own horn.
我知道，我表现得很好，不是在自吹自擂。
But, just to be clear,
但是，为了清楚起见，
that was totally me tooting my own horn the entire show.
整场演出都是我在自吹自擂。
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, where--
哇，哇，哇，哇，哪里——
Hey! We thought we'd celebrate.
嘿！我们想庆祝一下。
Yeah. Whee!
是的。哇！
Not for this big boy.
不是为了这个大男孩。
Honey, I am so sorry that we doubted you.
亲爱的，我很抱歉我们曾经怀疑你。
Today, you proved that you really can do it all.
今天，你证明了你真的可以做到一切。
And we can't wait to see you do it all again tomorrow
我们迫不及待想看你明天在足球赛上再次展现这一切。
at your soccer game.
对。明天。
- Right. Tomorrow. - Yeah.
- 对，明天。 - 是的。
Unless it gets canceled. Got to go.
除非它被取消。我得走了。
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, hey. Hey!
哇，哇，哇，哇，嘿。嘿！
Not without a hug.
不抱一下不行。
- Huh? Get in here. - Huh? Aw.
- 嗯？过来这里。 - 嗯？哦。
Tuba hug. Oh.
大号拥抱。哦。
- Tuba. - [grunting]
- 大号。 - [咕哝声]
Oh, no. She's in the parent trap.
哦，不。她被困在家长陷阱里了。
She has to get back to the game.
她得回到比赛中去。
We have to do something.
我们得做点什么。
I got it! I'm a genius!
我明白了！我真是个天才！
You know, Dicky's right.
你知道，迪基说得对。
I'm starting to think you're the boy who cried genius.
我开始觉得你就是那个总喊自己是天才的男孩。
- Tuba. - Tuba, tuba, tuba, tuba, tuba.
长号。长号，长号，长号，长号，长号。
- Tu-- - Okay. Okay, okay.
长——好吧。好吧，好吧。
That's a good enough hug. Good-bye!
这个拥抱够好了。再见！
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
嘿，哇，哇，哇，哇，哇，哇。
Right now is the perfect time for a celebratory ice cream.
现在正是庆祝时吃冰淇淋的完美时刻。
Yep.
没错。
[bell rings]
（铃声响起）
[gasps] Got to go!
[喘气] 得走了！
- Anne, why? - It wasn't me, I swear!
- 安妮，为什么？ - 真的不是我，我发誓！
Thanks so much.
非常感谢。
Now I got to get back to that game.
现在我得回到那场比赛了。
You only have four minutes.
你只剩下四分钟了。
Four minutes? That's not enough time!
四分钟？那时间不够啊！
I'm never gonna make it.
我永远也赶不上了。
[sighs]
[叹气]
Aw, forget it.
唉，算了吧。
I really can't do it all.
我真的做不到所有事情。
There is one way.
有一种方法。
We could take the cart.
我们可以用推车。
But what about your business? Look at all those customers.
但你的生意怎么办？看看那些顾客。
But we don't love selling hot dogs.
但我们并不热爱卖热狗。
Not like you love playing the tuba.
不像你热爱吹大号。
Or playing soccer.
或是踢足球。
Besides, we said we'd give up our hot dog business
而且，我们说过如果我们放弃热狗生意
if it was the right thing for you.
如果这对你是正确的事。
And that's what we're gonna do.
这就是我们要做的。
Aww, you guys.
哦，你们真是。
I thought that was a total lie.
我以为那完全是骗人的。
Oh, it was.
哦，确实是。
100%.
百分之百。
But we mean it now.
但现在我们是认真的。
Oh, and, uh, three minutes.
哦，还有，三分钟。
We'll get you there.
我们会帮你搞定的。
You just worry about getting changed.
你只需担心换衣服的事。
No problem.
没问题。
Come on, let's go.
来吧，我们走。
- Okay.
好的。
Thank you guys so much!
非常感谢你们！
You're the best brothers ever!
你们是最好的兄弟！
- Rock! - Got it.
岩石！明白了。
[all grunt]
（所有人哼声）
There's my game. I think it's already started.
那是我的比赛。我想已经开始了。
- Gopher hole! - Going for the hole.
地鼠洞！冲向洞口。
No, don't go for the hole! It's a gopher hole!
不，别冲向洞口！那是地鼠洞！
That's what I said!
我就是这么说的！
I'm so confused!
我完全糊涂了！
[rattling] - Whoa!
（咔哒声）哇！
Oof. I did it!
哎哟。我做到了！
I saved it! I'm Do-it-all Dawn!
我救到了！我是多面手Dawn！
Oh, whoops.
哦，哎呀。
Wrong game.
搞错了游戏。
My team's over there. Excuse me.
我的队伍在那边。借过一下。
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, and there will be a hot dog cart
哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，马上会有个热狗摊
coming here any moment, so feel free to help yourself.
随时会来这里，所以请随意享用。
[bell rings] - No brakes!
没有刹车！
[upbeat music]
（欢快音乐）
I'm sorry.
对不起。
I should have listened to you guys.
我应该听你们的。
Ah, don't be so hard on yourself, kiddo.
啊，别太苛责自己，孩子。
So you got benched for a game, and you had to quit band.
所以你被禁赛了一场比赛，还不得不退出了乐队。
I mean, nobody can do it all.
我是说，没有人能面面俱到。
Even your mom, who has a full-time job
即使是你的妈妈，她有一份全职工作
and takes care of you four, can't do everything.
还要照顾你们四个，也不可能做到所有事情。
Last night's lasagna, for example.
比如昨晚的千层面。
Sorry. It was a miss.
对不起。搞砸了。
I love you so much.
我非常爱你。
[bell rings] - [gasps]
[铃声响起] - [吸气声]
- [groans] [laughter]
Mom, you're a genius.
妈妈，你真是天才。
Oh, thank you, sweetie.
哦，谢谢你，宝贝。
- Doesn't mean anything.
- Totally hollow. - Does it to everybody.
♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
[whistling]
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 耶！ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ 耶！ ♪